New York Regional Society of Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery Records
New York Regional Society of Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery Records
1943-1969
1960-1969
New York Regional Society of Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery
2 linear feet (2 cartons)
Mss.arc
New York Academy of Medicine Library. Rare Book Room.
Historical Statement
The members of an informal organization of plastic surgeons founded the New York Regional Society of Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery (NYRSPS) in 1960. The goal of the organization was to increase and extend the knowledge of plastic surgery, reconstructive surgery, and tissue transplantation at monthly meetings. The organization also sought to foster personal and professional relationships among the members. The NYRSPS played a prominent role in the creation of a reconstructive and plastic surgery section within the New York Academy of Medicine in 1966. As of 2011, the society exists as the New York Regional Society of Plastic Surgeons.
Scope and Content
The collection is comprised mainly of correspondence and clippings. Other materials included are meeting programs and minutes.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the catalog of The New York Academy of Medicine Library. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Surgery, Plastic -- New York Metropolitan Area -- Societies, etc.; Surgery, Plastic.; New York Academy of Medicine. Section on Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery.; New York Regional Society of Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery.
Container List
- New York Regional Society of Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery Records
  - Correspondence, 1960-June 1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, July-December 1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, January-April 1965 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, May-December 1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, January 1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, February 1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, March 1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, April-August 1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, September-December 1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, January-May 1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, June-December 1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, 1943-1959 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Clippings, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Clippings, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Clippings, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Clippings, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Clippings, January-March 1964 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Clippings, April-December 1964 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Clippings, January-October 1965 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Clippings, November-December 1965 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Clippings, January-March 1966 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Clippings, April-August 1966 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Clippings, September-October 1966 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Clippings, October-November 1966 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Clippings, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Constitution and By-Laws (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Minutes, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Minutes, March 1962-February 1963 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Minutes, 1963-April 1969 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Assorted Programs, 1961-June 1965 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Assorted Programs, October 1965-June 1966 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Assorted Programs, November 1966-May 1967 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Assorted Programs, June 1967-March 1968 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - History of Medicine I (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - History of Medicine II (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - NYAM Section on Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Economics Committee I (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Economics Committee II (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Assorted Small Booklets (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Applications for Membership I (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Applications for Membership II (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Assorted Member Lists, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Assorted Member Lists, 1965-1969 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 48)
Provenance
Donated by the New York Regional Society of Plastic and Reconstructive Surgery.